She was a cop looking for corruption in all the wrong places.
And she's a mother raising a boy who's begun to ask why his mom packs a.38.
It's undercover mother.
Hey, guys. Ben, you know your bedtime, right?
1 a.m.
Ben, you know your bedtime, right?
Okay, none. He was worth a shot.
Honey, terrible news.
We're gonna have to miss the parents' meeting.
Gosh darn it.
My car won't start.
What did you do to it?
Nothing. Jason Siever, you are just trying to get out of this parents' meeting
because it's boring.
You think you know me so well.
Oh, no, I know I know you.
I know I know you.
I know you think you know me.
Well, I know you well enough to know you think.
I only think.
I know you.
I knew you'd say that.
I knew you'd say...
Stop! Here, look, just take my car.
Thanks, Mike. You're a prince.
Yeah, and aren't you to remember, this is a car and not a toy.
Treat it that way.
Yes, sir. So why would you lend them your car?
Well either they gotta fill up the gas tank or they're not going back.
Either way, I win.
I wanna watch something good.
Show me that smile, love, again.
Show me that smile.
Don't waste another minute on your crying.
We're nowhere near the end.
We're nowhere near the best.
It's ready to begin.
Oh, oh. As long as we got each other, we got the world spinning right in our hands,
baby. You and me.
We gotta be the luckiest dreamers who never quit dreaming As long as we keep on
giving We can take anything that comes our way Baby, let us shine all the time We
got each other sharing the laughter and the love
I'm not crazy about spending an evening debating whether or not the school cafeteria
should serve beans and weenies, which by the way I'm dead against.
But we do have a responsibility as parents.
Maggie, I'm crushed.
every bit as responsible and adult as you are.
Oh. Hey, chuckle head, blow it out your tailpipe.
Are you quite finished?
Yes. Sure you don't want to pull up alongside him and moon him?
Come on, Maggie, it's the middle of winter.
I know that hidden somewhere beneath that juvenile exterior is a responsible person.
Thank you. Want to steer?
Oh, geez! Come on, relax.
We're going to make it to the meeting, and then, oh, wow.
What? Well, that movie theater back there, they're playing a man and a woman.
Oh, what a wonderful movie.
Remember when we saw it for the first time?
Of course I do.
It was our first date.
No, it was our second date.
On the first date, I picked you up at the women's lib rally.
Oh, no, no, no.
You didn't pick me up.
I picked you up.
Yeah. Jason, let's go see it.
Oh, what about the meeting?
Well, we could put in a token of parents and then duck out.
Boy, I don't know.
La, da, da, da, da, da, da, da, da, da, da, da.
We have our responsibility.
Da, da, da, da, da, da, da, da, da, da, da, da, da, da, da, da, You were just
convincing me a minute ago that we should probably.
We gotta get him turning in.
We gotta vote him out.
All right. Vote him out.
All right, already.
Enough with the freaking talk.
Let's call for a vote.
All those in favor signify by saying aye.
Aye. Anybody opposed?
No! Ayes have it.
Motion is carried.
Beans and weenies it is.
Aw. Salvador Babac, you're trying to railroad this through because you've got the
school weenie contract.
Put a cork in it, Yvonne, huh?
Roll call. Roll call.
Jason, the movie starts in 15 minutes.
Well, wait now.
No, don't attract attention.
I'll sneak out.
You can follow me in a couple minutes.
Well, you get to leave first.
You want to put it to a vote?
No. You go.
I'll be the adult.
You sneak out.
Yvonne, we wasted enough time on this.
Besides, you don't even have a kid in this school.
Oh, sure. Bring that up again.
We can't. All right.
Next item on the agenda is whether we should establish a dress code for our little
monkeys here at Dewey High.
Anybody have anything to say?
Anybody have anything intelligent to say?
Yo, Doc! Go ahead.
Pardon me? Say what you want to say about this dress code deal.
Oh, well, actually, I was just going to, um, say that, uh, I don't think the dress
code is the school's business.
I think the children and their parents together should decide what's proper, and why
do we want to stifle that communication?
Whoa! Oh, you mean you actually want your teenage kids to communicate with you?
Yes, Mr. Hanks.
I want to know exactly what's on their minds.
I couldn't live like that.
Wait a minute, are we saying that we as parents, we don't want to be involved in the
shaping of our kids' ideas and their goals, their ambitions?
You haven't met my little Newton.
Well, if that's how you feel, Braxton, then why stop at a dress code?
Why not have full military uniforms?
We'll give them all little burr haircuts.
Is that a motion, Doc?
No. No. No, who here understands what I'm trying to say?
Oh, I do.
I do. You're saying that we should let the kids discover who they're going to be.
Yes. And if that means they're going to rebel a little bit, so what?
Exactly. And if that means they're going to be putting safety pins in their ears,
fine. No, I wasn't gonna go that far.
Bringing small caliber pistols to school.
No problem. Because that's what they're going to be doing if we keep on serving them
beans and wheat noodles.
That's a lot.
Thanks, Yvonne. Yes.
Maggie. What's going on?
Uh, excuse me.
I'm just trying to make a point here.
Well, I thought we were trying to make a movie.
Oh, we will.
Just, uh, help us.
Uh, you know, my wife, lovely, respected journalist Maggie.
And, Maggie, why don't you tell these people how you would feel if they imposed a
dress code at Dewey High?
Oh, I'd love it.
Well, hey. You would hate a dress code.
Jason, I don't want to argue about this.
No, not at all.
Just help me out.
I'm telling people that a dress code is wrong.
It's wrong. I -I don't think it is.
Hey, wait, wait, wait, Maggie didn't have the benefit of my opening remarks here,
and, uh, because I know you, and I know you'd agree.
Well, Jason, I know myself, and I don't agree.
Oh. You can't, uh, side with these people when they're on a thing.
Because this... It's a ridiculous thing.
It's ridiculous. But it makes sense.
Well, not to any thinking person.
Wait, wait, wait.
Oh, okay, okay, okay, Jason.
Okay. So, so how does a thinking person suggest
we teach our kids respect for the learning process and help them build character?
Oh, right. Yeah, wait, wait, wait.
Yeah, hey, hey.
Clothes. Clothes do not build character.
Huh. Talk to Don Johnson.
I don't want to talk to Don Johnson.
Well, maybe I do.
So would I.
Okay, Maggie, think, please.
Think. You are a liberal humanist.
No, Jason, you are.
And you are always getting us confused.
Uh, I know that, Maggie, once you've had a chance to think about this...
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
...you will realize that, um...
Wait a minute, wait a minute.
Are you implying that because I disagree with you, I'm not thinking?
No, I'm just saying you're...
you're a little distracted.
Distracted? Yes. You,
she, came in here tonight with nothing on her mind other than sneaking out to some
stupid movie. Well, whose idea was the stupid movie in the first place?
I just mentioned that it was playing.
Oh, sure, with that come -hither look in your eyes.
Is this a come -hither look?
Not to me.
And who is humming?
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
Excuse me, excuse me.
What's the name of that movie?
Oh, forget the movie, please.
Fine, fine. You brought it up.
Exactly. Hey, hey.
Listen, this is far too important an issue for us to decide about it without using
reason instead of ignorance.
Ignorance? Wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait.
Ignorance? Now, there's a very interesting word.
If you know that meaning of...
If you look it up in your dictionaries, you would see that ignorant doesn't mean
dumb, for instance.
Ignorant means uninformed.
As, well, here's my wife, Maggie, who is certainly not dumb, a very bright woman,
but, well, ignorant.
In this case, in this case, in one case, just this one, an isolated answer.
Not always, not always.
But just this one.
Boy, I am hungry.
Are you hungry?
I'm hungry. Shall we stop and eat?
What do you feel like?
I feel like dirt.
Oh, well, let's go to the International House of Dirt.
Yeah, well, uh, I have a better idea.
Why don't we just pull in here and see if they have a midnight showing of a man and
a woman, hmm?
Well, I'll check with the cashier.
You just keep smiling.
Ha ha. Da da da da da da da da da da.
La da da da da da da da da.
Ya da da ya da da da da da.
Ha ha. I'm sorry.
Hey, don't you think you're overreacting just a little bit?
It's a two -strike camp out on the night with the bases loaded.
But Marvelous Mike, the fiery right -hander, doesn't worry as he eyes the crowd.
He checks the signals,
takes a deep breath,
reaches for the rosin bag, spits...
Were you just pitched the stupid ball?
I just did, stay right three, two, out.
Ah! Ben? I'm down on my last man.
Ben! What? Stay right one.
Hey! Ben, you're supposed to be in bed by nine o 'clock.
I was. Nobody said anything about how I'm gonna stay there.
Would you just leave my buddy Ben alone, all right?
He and I are trying to get a little healthy exercise before we turn in.
Yeah! So why don't you just...
...stay right, too?
I hate you.
Fine, fine, fine.
You guys do what you want, but I sure wouldn't want to be in your shoes, Mom and Dad
walk through that door and see how openly you disobeyed them.
Wait, wait, wait.
Oh, yeah, good clean game of baseball.
Wait a minute.
My controller's not working.
Hmm. Alaparte, you're a slacker!
I win! Thank you, Mom.
Uh -oh. Uh, Mom, hi.
Look, Ben, this is the last time I'm gonna tell you, go to bed.
Mom, I can explain.
Good night, boys.
See you in the morning.
This could be a trick.
Uh... Mom, where's Dad?
Who? Uh, tall guy, nice smile, looks like a talk show host.
Oh, him? Uh, he's at the movies.
Fight. Hi, boys.
Mother home yet?
Uh, blonde woman?
Looks like Donna DeVarona.
Yeah, that's her.
Upstairs. Great. That's great.
Okay, good night, boys.
Wow, he didn't send me to bed either.
What do you say we go for a doubleheader?
No, I think I'll turn in.
Steve, I like you!
I'm sorry. Taxi.
Oh. Maggie, anger is not something that should be left inside to seethe and fester.
Jason, you make our marriage sound like a boil that needs lancing.
Okay, that's good.
Come on, go with that.
Jason, I'd rather not talk about this right now because I might say or do something
that I'd regret.
What, like leaving me stranded outside the mighty fine arts cinema?
No, I said something that I'd regret.
All right, look, I am sorry that I was rude.
I admit that I was thoughtless.
I admit I got a little carried away.
Oh, honey, it's okay, because I know how frustrating it must be to deal with someone
as ignorant as I am.
Maggie. Ignorance is such a terrible burden.
I explained I was using the term ignorant in its classic sense.
Yeah, I know you can't be this upset over the word ignorant, over that word.
I know that you're sublimating.
Tell me what you're sublimating.
Sublimating? Well, I'll tell you what I'm sublimating.
I am sublimating at this very instant a sincere desire to tell you exactly what I
feel about psychiatric terms like sublimating.
All right, I won't use psychiatric terms.
Just tell me what's got you so upset.
You really don't know, do you?
Well, not precisely, no.
Why, it's stunned that you don't know, Jason, since I don't have a thought in my
head that you haven't put there.
That's what I thought.
No, no, no, that's not what I thought.
Well, I'll tell you what I thought.
I thought that you really meant it when you said that the best thing about our
marriage was the fact that we were both individuals with ideas, ambitions, and
identities. Well, you know I do.
I know you did.
Until tonight, I heard you blurt out how you really feel.
I didn't blurt.
So you thought about it before you said it?
Oh, my God.
I was... I always have a...
You've taken a word out of context, and you've blown it out of all proportion.
Oh, there I go, showing my classic ignorance again.
Come on. You know as well as I do.
I love the fact that you have your own ideas, you have your own identity.
I don't even mind a little disagreement, Maggie.
I thrive on it.
Well, Jason, you're in for some real fun.
Okay, now I'm getting angry.
Go with that.
Maggie. Don't supplement.
Come on, you're so upset because this one silly, stupid little remark that
accidentally blurted out...
Ah! So you admit that you blurted?
Oh, are we back to that again?
Jason, you are the psychiatrist, and I'm surprised that you don't know when a person
just blurt out something.
It is usually how they really feel.
Oh. Nuts! See?
Do you know, I don't see any point in continuing this.
Do you see any point in continuing this?
No, I don't.
Well, I just think that the way you're acting tonight, Maggie, I don't even know
you. Well, that's exactly how I feel!
Oh, well, blurt, blurt.
I'm sorry. Ben, I cannot sit here and watch you eat that for breakfast.
So close your eyes.
Do you guys have any idea what's going on?
You are not gonna believe this.
Mom and Dad are fighting.
How'd you know?
Well, first, Dad slept on the couch, and second, he didn't just dress up to go
jogging. He actually went.
Not only that, Mom actually said we should get our own breakfast.
Well, we've got to do something about this.
Why? Mike, this is Mom and Dad we're talking about.
I mean, at their age, somebody has to look out for them.
True. Yeah, I think we should clear this thing up before Ben becomes a total porker.
Hey, I'm making the best out of a bad situation.
I know what would work.
I mean, they couldn't be mad at each other if one of their kids were in trouble,
right? No, no, no, no, no.
Carol, I'm always in trouble.
No, no, no, I mean, like, hurt.
Forget it. Wait a second.
Oh, no, I got it.
I got it.
Oh, this is great.
So simple, so perfect, so right.
You know, sometimes my brain frightens me.
All right, now get this.
I'm gonna send Mom a huge bouquet and a wimpy apology from Dad.
That's your idea?
Yeah. Mike, it'll never work.
Well, did on the Cosby show.
That's TV. This is real life.
Hold it. You're saying the cosplay show isn't real?
Oh, Mike, how do you know it's Dad who should apologize to Mom?
Well, Carol, whenever a man and a woman fight, every guy on the planet knows who has
to apologize. Honey?
Honey? Honey? Honey!
What? Well, I was wondering if maybe I could just have a word with you before you
went to work.
Well, I'm running kind of late this morning, Jason.
I'm interviewing Governor Cuomo.
How about tonight?
Well, I was hoping we could, you know, talk just before you left, because I've been
thinking about the way things
sometimes get out of hand, and events gain a momentum of their own.
And, uh, then we end up saying things we don't mean.
I know... Gotta go.
Thank you. Thank you.
Thank you. Hey, hold on a second.
I can't. My interview's in half an hour.
Well, don't you think you should dress for it?
Jason, I don't need a fashion critique.
I hardly slept a wink last night, and I'm not thinking very clearly this morning.
Well, this is beyond fashion.
I mean, you approach the governor dressed like that, and his bodyguards are gonna
wrestle you to the ground.
Oh, so what do you wear when you interview the governor?
Well, come on, I'm just saying this is a respected public official.
This is Mario Cuomo, not Bozo Cuomo.
So you're saying the clothing has something to do with character?
Oh, of course.
No! No, no, no, no.
Too late, Jason.
You said it.
You feel the same way I do.
I don't. You do.
No, I don't.
Just because you feel one way about certain things doesn't mean I have to feel the
same way. Exactly.
That's exactly the point I've been trying to make.
But you tricked me.
Honey, I wouldn't have stooped so low if I didn't love you.
So I deserve to be tricked?
I guess I do.
I'm really sorry about what I said last night.
Honey, you embarrassed me in front of all those people.
I'm sorry. I was ignorant.
But just for the record,
I still don't believe in dress codes at school.
And just for the record, I'm still for them.
So we can either debate about it or we...
Excuse me. Dr.
Jason Siever? Oh, honey.
You shouldn't have.
That's my job.
Oh. Jason, I love you even when you think you don't agree with me.
Love, Maggie. Aw, honey, that's so sweet.
Well, I just thought that after...
I wish I had been, you know, my...
More flowers. These are for Maggie Siever.
Oh. And, hey, just seeing people like you is tipping up for me.
Yeah. Jason, how sweet.
Well, I, uh...
Maggie, dearest, how could I have been so wrong?
I'm a complete wimp.
Love, Jason. Oh, honey, don't you think you're being a little hard on yourself?
Nah.